John V. Dowdy, Sr. papers, Inclusive: 1926-1986, undated; Bulk: 1952-1972, undated.
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
John V. Dowdy, Sr. papers
Inclusive: 1926-1986, undated; Bulk: 1952-1972, undated.
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
7
Dowdy, John
519 document, 6 record, and 4 oversize boxes
The John Dowdy papers span the period of his life from the mid-1920s to his death in 1995. While the bulk of the papers are from his congressional years (1952-1972), there are also considerable materials in the Personal series pertaining to his years as Court Reporter and District Attorney (1935-1952), as well as the series covering his trial and imprisonment (1965-1974).
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
John Vernard Dowdy was born in Waco, McLennan County, Texas, on February 11, 1912. He spent his early years in Rusk, Texas, and graduated from high school in Henderson, Texas, in 1928. He attended the College of Marshall (now East Texas Baptist University) from 1929 to 1931.
In the spring of 1932, Dowdy began working in a law office at Center, Texas, as a secretary, and in August became the official court reporter of the newly established 123rd Judicial District of Texas. From January 1, 1937, to January 1, 1945, he served as court reporter of the 3rd Judicial District in Athens, Texas. During this time he was admitted to the bar and began practicing law in 1940. Dowdy was elected District Attorney of the 3rd Judicial District in 1944, took office on January 1, 1945, and served eight years until his election to Congress in 1952.
Dowdy was elected as a Democrat to the 82nd Congress to fill a vacancy caused by the resignation of Tom Pickett. In the House, he served on the House Administration Committee and the Post Office and Civil Service Committee, serving as chairman of the Postal Operations Subcommittee in 1955 and 1956. He later served on the Judiciary and District of Columbia committees.
As a member of the Judiciary Committee, he authored legislation for protecting National Defense facilities; amended criminal laws to embrace air piracy; empowered postal authorities to police the mail; and proposed reforms in the control of obscene, pornographic, and subversive literature.
Dowdy was elected to ten Congresses serving from September 23, 1952, to January 3, 1973. However, his years of service were not without controversy. On March 31, 1970, he was indicted by a federal grand jury in Baltimore, Maryland, on charges of conspiracy, perjury, and promoting bribery. The indictment charged that Dowdy allegedly accepted a $25,000 bribe on September 22, 1965, to intervene in a federal investigation of Monarch Construction Company of Silver Springs, Maryland.
Consequently, Dowdy was arraigned on the indictments on April 10, 1970. The trial began November 8, 1971, and he was convicted on December 30, 1971. Subsequently, he announced his retirement from Congress on January 18, 1972, and began a six-month prison sentence on January 18, 1974.
In documents donated by the Dowdy family following John's death in 1995, tapes, correspondence, and trial transcripts indicate that Dowdy may have been set up by those who opposed his conservative stance to urban renewal. These extensive documents are open to researchers.
Scope and Content
The John Dowdy papers span the period of his life from the mid-1920s to 1986. While the bulk of the papers are from his congressional years, 1952-1972, there are also considerable materials in the Personal and Political series pertaining to his years as a court reporter and District Attorney (1935-1952). Another series, Trial and Imprisonment, dates mainly from 1970 to 1974, with a few letters written as early as 1965 and as late as 1978.
Dowdy’s Congressional papers (1952-1972) contain government files for office administration, agencies and commissions, departments, committees, correspondence, and legislation. Points of interest include the District of Columbia Committee files, the Judiciary Committee files, and the extensive correspondence related to urban renewal. The correspondence comes from every state and usually deals with governmental overspending and scandals related to local projects.
Dowdy’s Personal papers contain information about his family, court reporter and legal files, and media materials such as 3" reel-to-reel tapes, 12" vinyl records, 16 mm film, cassettes, and video tapes. Some of the material has been digitized and captured on DVD and/or made into mp3 files. It is rounded out with campaign material, including speeches given on the campaign trail and at numerous civic meetings and events. Publications in this series show Dowdy’s conservative roots.
The Trial and Imprisonment series contains legal documents related to the trial, including appeals, FBI and defense reports, personalities, proceedings, and a complete trial transcript. A large portion of the series is supportive correspondence from people in Dowdy’s district, Texas, and throughout the United States.
Arrangement
The John Dowdy papers are arranged in eight series: Administrative, Agencies and Commissions, Committees, Correspondence, Departments, Legislative, Personal, and Trial. The collection was re-processed in 2017-2018 and an Administrative series was added.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 7. Acquired 1971-03-31
Related Resources
Related references
Ben Rogers, Sarah Kenton, and Nancy Arreola. Papers of John V. Dowdy, Sr. Finding Aid. 1998 April.
John V. Dowdy, Sr. papers, Accession #7, Baylor Collections of Political Materials, W. R. Poage Legislative Library, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Dowdy, John -- Archives -- Indexes.
Subjects (Organizations)
Democratic Party (U.S.); United States. Congress. House. Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.; United States. Congress. House.
Subjects
Equal rights amendment--United States.; Legislation--Texas.; Legislators -- Texas.; Political corruption -- United States.; Politicians -- Texas.; Public prosecutors--Texas.; Trials (Political crimes and offenses).; United States. -- Department of Housing and Urban Development.
Genres
16mm (photographic film size).; Audiocassettes.; Awards.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; DVDs.; Ephemera.; MP3.; Newsletters.; Open reel audiotapes.; Photographs.; Programs (Publications).; Questionnaires.; Records (Documents); Records and briefs.; Registers (Lists).; Speeches.; Trial and arbitral proceedings.; Videotapes.
- Administrative, 1939-1984, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Administrative series contains correspondence with requests, invitations, congratulations, and condolences. Material chronicles Dowdy’s visits to the counties he represented as well as his voting record. Alpha files round out the General subseries. The Post Offices subseries is organized by city and county, then year. News clippings, newsletters, news releases, and radio and television broadcast scripts make up the Press/Media subseries. Dowdy’s work on rivers within his district, especially the Trinity River, make up the bulk of the Projects subseries. The State of Texas subseries contains correspondence and subject files on education, employment, public welfare, and redistricting.
  - General, 1952-1972, undated; 1
    - Appreciation, 1965, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appreciation Dinner, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Appreciation Dinner, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Assassinations, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Athens, Texas (Water Bonds), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - B-Files, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - B-Files, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - B-Files, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - B-Files, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - B-Files, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - B-Files, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baptist Publications, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Beaumont Remedial Clinic, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C-Files, 1957, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - C-Files, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - C-Files, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - C-Files, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - C-Files, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - C-Files, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - C-Files, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - C-Files, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - C-Files, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Calendar of Events, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Calendar Requests, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Calendar Requests, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Calendar Requests, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Calendar Requests, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Calendar Requests, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Calendar Requests, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Calendar Requests, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Church Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Clifton, Texas, 1954-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Clerk of the House, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clerk of the House, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Clerk of the House, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Clerk of the House, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Clerk of the House, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Clerk of the House, 1967-1968, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Clubs, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Commendations (1 of 2), 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Commendations (2 of 2), 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Commendations, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Commendations, Testimonial DinnerDLNacogdoches, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Committee Assignments, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Committee Assignments, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Committee Assignments, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Committee Assignments, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Committee Assignments, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Condolences, Personal, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Condolences, Personal, 1956-1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Condolences, Personal, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Condolences and Congratulations, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1955-1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Congratulations, Personal (1 of 3), 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Congratulations, Personal (2 of 3), 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Congratulations, Personal (3 of 3), 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Congratulations, Personal, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Directory Requests, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Directory Requests, 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Directory Requests, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Directory Requests, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Congressional Directory Requests, 1968-1970, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1952-1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Record Requests, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Constituent Visits to DC, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Constitutional Restoration, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Contributions, Personal, 1954-1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Crackpots, 1955-1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - D-Files, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - D-Files, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - D-Files, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - D-Files, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - D-Files, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - D-Files, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - D-Files, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Debate Material, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Debate Topic (High School), 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Deep East Texas Economic Development District, Overall Program-Part 1, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Democratic National Committee, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Democratic National Congressional Committee, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Disbursements, 1952-1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - E-Files, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - E-Files, 1968-1970, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Employment, A, 1953-1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Employment, B, 1953-1959 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Employment, B, 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Employment, C, 1952-1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Employment, Census Employment Inquiries, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Employment, D, 1953-1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Employment, E, 1955-1964 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Employment, F, 1953-1963 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Employment, G, 1955-1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Employment, H, 1953-1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Employment, J, 1952-1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Employment, K, 1954-1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Employment, L, 1956-1964 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Employment, M, 1952-1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Employment, M, 1960-1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Employment, N, 1954, 1960, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Employment, O, 1954, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Employment, P, 1954-1964 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Employment, Q, 1955, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Employment, R, 1953-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Employment, S, 1953-1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Employment, S, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Employment, T, 1954-1964 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Employment, U-V, 1959, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Employment, W, 1953-1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - F-Files, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Federal Employees, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Federal Employment, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Federal Employment (1 of 3), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Federal Employment (2 of 3), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Federal Employment (3 of 3), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Federal Employment, A-B, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Federal Employment, C-F, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Federal Employment, G-M, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Federal Employment, N-V, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Federal Employment, W-Z, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Federal Employment, A-L, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Federal Employment, M-Z, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Federal Employment, A-L, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Federal Employment, Mc-Z, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Federal Employment, Clerk Applications, 1952-1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Federal Employment, Index, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Federal Employment, Overseas, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Federal Employment, Patronage, 1952, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Federal Employment, Patronage, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Federal Employment, Summer Jobs, 1956-1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Federal Employment, Summer Jobs, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Federal Employment, Summer Jobs, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Federal Employment, Summer Jobs, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Federal Employment, Summer Jobs, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Flag Requests, 1958-1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Flag Requests, 1966-1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Football Tickets (sampled), 1956-1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Form Letters, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters, 1967-1972 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Friendship House, 1952, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - G-Files, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - G-Files, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - G-Files, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Gifts (sampled), 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Gifts (sampled), 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Gifts (sampled), 1961-1965 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Gifts (sampled), 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - H-Files, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - H-Files, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - H-Files, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - H-Files, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - H-Files, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - H-Files, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Head, Heart, Health, Home (4H), 1969 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - High School Graduates, Lists and Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - High School Graduates, Mailing Lists, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - High School Graduates, Mailing Lists, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - High School Graduates, Mailing Lists, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - High School Graduates, Thank You, 1955-1962 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - High School Graduates, Thank You, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - I-Files, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Inauguration, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Inauguration, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Inauguration, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Inauguration, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1966-1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Development, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Insurance, 1952-1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - International Neighbors Club, 1955-1970 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1952-1955 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1952-1955 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Invitations, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Invitations, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Invitations, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Invitations, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Invitations (1 of 3), 1961 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Invitations (2 of 3), 1961 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Invitations (3 of 3), 1961 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1963 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1963 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1965 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Invitations (1 of 2), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Invitations (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Invitations, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Invitations, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, Speaking, 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Invitations, Speaking, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Invitations, Speaking, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Invitations, Speaking, 1960-1964 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - J-Files, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - J-Files, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - J-Files, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Johnson Administration, 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Johnson, Lyndon, News Clippings, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Johnson, Russell, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, Russell, 1965, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - K-Files, 1955-1964 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - K-Files, 1965-1967 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - K-Files, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - K-Files, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Kennedy, Robert, Assassination, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - L-Files, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - L-Files, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - L-Files, 1969-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Levine, Bill, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Liberty Lobby, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Liberty Lobby, 1970-1974, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - M-Files, 1955-1962 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - M-Files, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - M-Files, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - M-Files, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - M-Files, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - M-Files, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Mc-Files, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Mc-Files, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - McCarthy, Joseph, 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - N-Files, 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - N-Files, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - N-Files, 1969-1972 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Nations, Rivers, and Harbors Congress, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - O-Files, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - O-Files, 1968-1972 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Office, 1952-1959 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Office, 1961-1965 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Office, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Office, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Office, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Office, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Office, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Office, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Office, Clerkship, 1952-1962 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Office, District, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Office, Forms, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Office, Interoffice Correspondence (1 of 2), 1952-1969 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Office, Interoffice Correspondence (2 of 2), 1952-1969 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Office, Student Intern Program, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - P-Files, 1965-1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - P-Files, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - P-Files, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Patronage, Page, 1965-1967 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Patronage, Page, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Patronage, Page, 1969-1972 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - People to See in District, 1965-1970 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Petitions, 1955-1960 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Powell, General Adam C., 1960-1967 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - President Nixon’s Inaugural, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - President Nixion’s Inaugural, Publications, Official Guide Book, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Publications, “Analysis of Selected Recommendations of the Second Hoover Commission” (American Legion), 1956 January (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Baptist Standard, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Publications, The Catfish Farmer, Vol. 3, No. 2, 1971 March (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Publications, “Congressional District Data”, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Publications, Decision, 1964 Jan (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Publications, “Federal Jobs Overseas”, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Publications, The Hawkeye Odd Fellow, Vol. 7, No. 3, 1960 August (Box 30, Folder 10)